all right welcome to
our first in a long time project raising
on promoting game b project green b
companies corporations businesses
uh we're going to focus on mark
campbell's vision and intention for the
hour
and help move it forward as best we can
take it from there mark okay
thanks jubilee and thanks everybody for
coming
so when i i first posted this uh about
three weeks ago and i got
a lot of input from everyone um
i think at some point uh i'd like to
change it
from uh mark campbell's vision to
um the game be false
uh facebook groups vision
for driving um
business to game b companies we already
had a couple of discussions and thank
you
jubilee it's um
i've well first of all a little bit of
background on me so i've
i've i come from
it sounds weird to say it but i guess a
technical background because that wasn't
my
best that's not what i was best at but i
worked in the aircraft industry and i
worked on a couple initiatives
um to create um an apprenticeship
program
and to to to to gain
more rights for technical specialists so
working with groups for
over uh up to a year and over a year
and working with government regulators
and all that so
this what i what what i found work well
and also
working with um companies to create
databases
that function well and got used by
everyone
and what i found work best is to cast a
wide net
and find people at every strata
of usability or management level that
will
come into contact with that either that
software or that legislation or that
program that you're building it's it's
it's a
pain but what happens is
that you get everybody that's in that
room
that's involved with it now becomes like
an evangelist
and an advocate of that thing
when it finally gets developed and hits
the streets
so my ideally i would like to see
everybody in the facebook group
have some kind of input may be trapped
by that software that adriel was talking
about where they put their input in
and then it um it gets tracked and every
the programmers can comment on it and
other people can comment on it
and if it's easy to do and um
and urgent and important then it will
get done it's hard to do
but important equals or height but
important
it's a little lower and hard to do but
not important it just
drops off and you can see why so um
that is kind of like what i'd like to
see happen over the next year
so basically um we talked about them so
i'm just going to mention some of the
ideas an
app that an easy to use app
that gets adopted right away that allows
people and this is i think jubilee's
words the need for a meta app that pulls
all the information about game b
products and companies into
into one simple app it can rate
companies
um that are beneficial you can choose a
feature set
that is important to you break those
values it shows you companies
based on that and shows you the overall
ratings as well um
i think jubilee mentioned this it would
be kind of like a cancel culture that
actually works but gives you a road to
redemption a company a road to
redemption
so that you can see if a company is
doing well is improving over time
has done well has improved over time
hi alejandra welcome how are you
hi nice to see you hi
everybody
um so um basically just
a a little bit of a recap so a meta app
that's easy to use
that would show people a list of
companies
that have done beneficial things
in the past and how
they have done in the past few months
are they trending up are they trending
down and you can see that as well
so because we have that information it
will capture that
so this and this came out of the
previous meetings
um providing a software module to
companies so that they can begin the
process of incorporating their companies
into this list and app so they can start
it
and then the the people
in this work group
or committee will then uh help to
onboard that company
um and and track and verify that
information
um it can be crowdsourced at the
beginning
uh but if if they're if they provide
enough hooks
and they're easily verifiable then this
can grow when they can show the
connections to other companies their
suppliers
and such uh
start with small local businesses and
they could grow to provide a platform to
provide those businesses with a local
market
small companies will get priority and
prominence on the app
and you can add things like products and
ingredients lists later uh
bentley mentioned that you can buy these
ingredient lists so that's that's
something that can be added later
um i'm not sure who mentioned this but i
thought this was important how we can
make sure that only the data we want to
share gets shared with only companies
we know won't use it for bad purposes i
that seemed like it was important i'm
not sure how we'd do that but it has to
be something that
is considered
there's a lot of green washing that's a
tendency now that so
that again is something that has to be
considered when you're thinking about
um how you're going to verify this and
how you're going to make sure those
ratings that you have
are you still valid
uh moderators to keep the bots out i
i thought that was important as well and
um
so people want cheaper quality plus
metrics like companies from the good guy
there's one of the things that came up
is that there were three or four really
really good companies that
had this kind of intent but they weren't
used i never even heard of them until
um we did this uh the
well what was the other one um b corp
i contacted them but they they just
really didn't have
much of a desire i seem to get involved
with this so
that fell off the wayside but other
companies i never heard of b corp before
i never heard a good guide and never
heard of other companies
a lot of these companies but why so
that's a big thing
we have to kind of figure out why
because we want this to be used we want
this to be the killer app we want this
thing
to people to use the word for using it
like google
i want to buy i want to make a purchase
i i'm thinking about this
so i'm going to use this app to just
research and get the information right
away
and there's big companies that buy other
companies
so we want to know that too it's got to
be if that happens
then this thing goes gray or something
like that and it won't
rise to prominence until the rest of the
stuff is filled up
um this was i thought this was kind of
gritty you need something that tells you
when someone is being a bastard
you recognize that language carrie so
just uh you know something that's very
very simple very graphic
very intuitive that says this
you know this is is just something that
is trending the wrong direction i'm
going to point that out
radical transparency that's the ideal
that's the model
companies get prominence and points for
providing radical transparency
um that's the idea may never get there
but it's just the idea
and the app is built to to grow with
plug-in capability for the marketplace
for products
ingredients and contracts so at this
stage it's the casting of the white net
still trying to gather and even know
where we need input from i'm going to
need input from people who are just
neophyte users programmers
people who are business people and
people know
kind of where all the bodies are buried
you know
and so ideally in two months
i would like to be able to know whether
this is viable or not to go ahead
and a year to come up with a workable
list
and a basic functioning app
so that is that is the idea two months
go or no go
12 months something
anyways i'll open it up
so i was just looking up i'll start
go ahead oh so uh i was just looking at
the certified b
the b corporation that you mentioned i'd
forgotten that was there
um and just to clarify that has nothing
to do with game b
uh b corporation in that context is
benefit corporation in the u.s
corporation settings but it's it
overlaps in a kind of way because
they're trying to work for a better
world but i was
i don't know market if you'd already
looked to see that they
they do actually do ratings on b
corporations at several different
uh levels have you seen that
uh yeah i i love the idea of b
corp i um there's a few things
that when i contacted them i i
i really thought well if
if this if one of the key things they do
is just
miscall the b corps thing that would be
fantastic and they
i i emailed them and i i
i wanted to to do that but they just
just seemed very
reluctant what was your feeling well i
haven't communicated with them i was
just asking whether you're aware of
their rating system they have on the
site
uh adriel can you pull up my screen
share
so this is uh this is their rating for
greening
which is just the first company i saw on
their list so it's got a rating in 92.3
and then they have it broken down by
governance the
worker rating a community rating
environment customers and then they rate
each section
um so that was interesting now that's
that's not of course exactly what you're
talking about
um but it was a little closer than i'd
i hadn't checked on them in a year or so
so they've added a lot of features to
their site so
i just wanted us to to be aware that
that exists
um and then we could see whether we want
to
you know if the how is that overlap
enough that
this initiative doesn't have to go much
further or does it change the initiative
to find a different niche
or other stuff so
one question i have about this out of
the gates is this u.s only
most likely it's from what i know a b
corp is a u.s thing most likely
b corp is global b corp is global
where do you
like this site is global because i think
that oh this company was actually in
chile
the one that you were just looking at
which is interesting now is this
something that people
kept i guess is that close to what mark
was talking about where people have to
sort of sign up to get
audited and sort of they provide their
information in a questionnaire and then
that could summarize
a lot of stuff about b corps
um there's a b
corp is a company that's been
that has applied to and been certified
by b lab which is a non-profit
organization
and uh you have that the company has to
meet several pretty
stringent criteria uh
triple bottom line criteria people
planet
profit etc in order to be
certified and then they get an
independent audit
and they have to and they're audited
annually and they have to report
how they're doing so uh
the information becomes accessible on
the
on the b corp website as we're seeing
here
so that's one source of data
and now there's a there's a confusion
between
a b lab certified b corp
and a legally registered
public benefit corporation they're two
different things
okay
a a public benefit corporation also
referred to as b
corp which is what makes it confusing is
a type of legal entity
for all intents and purposes it's
essentially the same
as a c corp except
it is exempt from the mandate
to maximize profits for shareholders
okay so uh
it's incorporated specifically to be a
social enterprise
well it i think you can still have
it you just have to have a benefit
you can still maximize i mean you you
can still have that in the charter it
just means you have to have something
that
is an addition to that
i don't think you're not profit
motivated some of them are
right but it's it's triple bottom line
so of course you can make a profit
but your shareholders can't sue you
because you invested in the community
project
because right the problem with the c
corp
is that you know where you have
shareholders
and not all companies that have
are public companies right
be private company with private
shareholders but nonetheless
if the company decides to invest in a
community project
some shareholder can say wait a minute
that money could have come to us
right as a as a dividend why are you
wasting that money it could be
a profit for for the shareholders
so the the advantage of
registering as a public benefit
corporation
i think in washington they're called
social purpose organizations
is that they're social enterprises and
they're expressly
not designed exclusively to
produce profits for shareholders so
they're exempt from that liability
which enables them to be social
enterprises does that make sense
yeah i wanna i wanna that's i think
that's
that's just underlines something that is
so
critical is the confusion around this
and i think that's why
it's um we don't know anything about i
didn't know anything about b corp i
didn't know
anything about benefit corporations and
maybe that's one of the things maybe
that's a would be a
part of the mandate of this initiative
is to
make things like yeah you know get that
information out there and clear up clear
up all of this
because the c corp can become certified
by vlad
yes yeah yeah i i think i loved it
tell me harrison when you first heard of
beelab were you not impressed
did you not think that this could be a
force that could change the world
i i thought it was definitely going in
the right direction because
it is essentially if you look at their
criteria what it takes
in fact i actually applied to become a
corp at one point
with my social enterprise but what i
realized in doing it
and the feedback i got from them was i
mean
the bar is really quite high to get that
certification and it's really designed
for enterprise level corporations it's
not for
startups really um
and you know most of where the green
washing goes on
and the uh you know benefit
devoting uh profits to shareholders is
primarily at the enterprise level
so you know you got a lot of people say
oh corporations are so bad you know we
got to get rid of corporations
well actually things that have like uh
a uh public trust like for example drug
companies
where there's tremendous profits
that i i think that they should be
required by
law to become certified as b corp they
can
they can still be registered as a c corp
but if they're um certified a b
corp as well then that's when you get
the public transparency
and accountability as you can see on
your screen
so just looking from that um what's on
there
there's a few things that uh i see that
are are really good but i don't i don't
see a a drill down capability to say
how they came up with those cores or
what um
how how they're doing over time or
um an ability to choose what's relevant
to me so somebody else has come up with
that score
so there's a few things missing from
there from
what just came up in those initial
discussions about what this app
could be um
just at first blush alejandro
have you heard of b corp
alejandra can you hear me sorry i have
having some technical issues
yes i have and they do exist in
argentina and in brazil
and i don't know exactly about the rest
of latin america
but um it's kind of new um
a few years that is happening here as
well
and they mostly operate under the
under the sort of umbrella concept of
for profit for good
um which is pretty much where i
understand how it came
down from the the us in legal terms
i i think there is no i i would
need to check on that
now a um field representation before
it was just another type of uh regular
company
um that that set itself up
uh to reinvest a percentage of the
the the profits either on their people
in the company or in a social
house so i don't know about the details
but i can i can look that up
but yes they do exist here
so i get i get i still it still feels
like they're doing good work but it's
just
why wouldn't they um be pushing
to have this at people's fingertips so
that
everybody because initially that's what
this
this this app could that we're talking
about
could be this thing that would let you
know right away
um where all the best companies to even
invest or know about or do any kind of
business with
our well they're they're a particular
niche
you know they're filling a particular
niche uh
they don't have all the public benefit
corporations
on their site that's not their bailiwick
right
so the the app that you're talking about
would want to include
not only the b lab certified b course
but also excuse me those you know
startups
and social enterprises and uh
other companies that have registered as
a public benefit corporation for a
social
purpose organization well i think
beyond that i'd like to clarify that
so you initially mentioned game b
corporations or game b
businesses um so is it
i mean are we limiting it to
you know businesses from people in the
game b community or is it any business
that we think the game b community
would appreciate or is it any business
that has
you know kind of what's this what's the
scope here
no no yeah that's and the criteria is
still
very much open kerry did you have
something to
add yeah i was just wondering how much
you know if you want to be certified as
one of these b
cups how much do they actually charge
you for being registered
harrison do you know how much he charges
it
if you're a smaller company they charge
you less
right i remember reading that i think uh
going back to bentley's question it's
it's that's the criteria originally i
thought
uh we come up with some criteria that we
would would fit but it's not restricted
to just companies
within game b but the original
crowdsourcing
could be from the gay be the game b
facebook group members and that just
it looks like the prices start at a
thousand dollars and
cap out roughly at 50 000 and then after
you do more than a billion annual sales
it says based on the size and complexity
of your business
yeah there you go
so a minimum of a thousand per year
just going back to criteria of who
what companies would be tracked
originally
from those discussions we came down to
small companies so in my mind bentley it
would be
if if you thought a company could fit
the bill you could put it forward and
then
um some group would vet it
some internal group would vet it that's
that's how i pictured it
what did you what was your initial
criteria
for betting
well just i yeah just just based on
i don't even know if that's um
applicable but
i i guess i was just anything that could
be considered omni-win a benefit
uh environmentally socially that type of
thing where um
the the person you're not taking a huge
amount of money for yourself
uh you have you have all the money
coming in where you're getting it from
your suppliers radical transparency as
well
so basically triple bottom line is that
right
well i have no idea what triple bottom
line is but does that sound like triple
bottom line to you harrison that
maybe give it yeah the concept of triple
bottom line is
people profit and planet
okay right uh the three ps
so you know you do you can do well
while doing good is the idea right
so um a company that is
doing things for their people or their
community
as well as uh things for the planet
right their products or services are
actually beneficial or green or
sustainable or whatever and
yeah they're profitable
okay i've had a question uh dropped a
drill down you can add a self back in
at any point um who is the user
of this at the end mark is it someone
looking to invest
someone looking to buy a single product
like who
are you envisioning using the app
ethical shoppers i would think
yeah everyone everyone yeah
so and and anyone that's interested to
see
you know like it would just be
it would be so simple to use
that and it would just it people might
have a curiosity thing
you know they're they're thinking about
investing they're thinking about buying
stuff
and somebody say didn't this company do
this this and this and
aren't they or enthused carries words
aren't they bastards
and you can look at it and say well no
they were bastards two years ago but
really they're they're doing really well
now because and
this is a real thing you don't have to
worry about
some third party telling you um
dirk on this corporation you've got that
actual information right there
so ethical shoppers but like anyone
that's interested
going back to the point about
transparency and accountability
bcorp does a pretty good job of it for
the people for the
corporations that are registered sp
course
but on the social enterprises they are
also by law
required to publicly
report how well they're doing on
accomplishing their social mission
now we do that just by putting the
report on our website
so that data is also publicly available
so why why are you required parenting
it's required by law if you're
registered as a public benefit
corporation
you're registered okay yeah for u.s
companies for u.s companies exactly and
actually the the social benefit
corporation or public benefit
corporation
is also in other countries as well like
i was living in taiwan for a while
and they had it there too so it's
becoming it's becoming a global movement
because they may vary as far as
requirements and reporting requirements
and stuff
but yeah
so i so yeah so i guess the question is
so
um yeah so b corp's probably the closest
thing
is everyone on this call no one else is
aware of any other existing
initiatives that are doing what we're
talking and i and i think
mark and sounds like harrison you've
done research
to determine that because that's kind of
one of the first steps in a project is
don't well one one question is do you
want to include non-profits or not
uh i i imagine non-profits would be
preferred
well i um yeah i i don't know why you'd
exclude them
originally i thought on a list
is there um yeah i guess so
i was thinking at first would there be
interest and even general interest in
seeing the non-profits but i guess there
would be
i i originally thought there are several
non-profits that you know produce
products and services
or have spin-off companies oh okay okay
that's
uh right that's a good that's a good
point
yeah i think profitabil profitedness is
not a uh
it's not a factor i mean something we'd
want to show
but that's not a deciding factor unless
you'd say that a non-profit would
get even more points because the goal is
the the the main initiative
or and i don't know mark this this idea
came out before you knew about game b
or is it in response to what you've been
learning in game b or is it unrelated
i think it's always been there um okay
i um yeah both like 20 years
and i think everybody's had anybody
who's ever
gone to do business with somebody and
say i wish i knew
if if this this person or this company
had done you know trash in the in the
past
you know that's always been there i
think i've always
had that yeah so we wouldn't i can't
imagine we'd exclude it and wouldn't
have a requirement that you'd be
incorporated or requirement that you'd
be
you know anything i mean you could be
selling soaps out of your
out of your car
and you could potentially be included
right
i had a question about um we had
discussed before
that although game b corporations are
the
important ones that if you don't have
the game a corporations in there it's
hard to compare them
are you still looking to include all of
them or just the ones like
kind of like b corp does just the good
ones
oh that's a good that's a really good
question
um um at first i wasn't thinking that
but you're right it would be a way to
compare and just crowdsource it because
if they're they're gonna be
non-transparent
but just crowdsource it and say okay
these are what the bottom feeders are
doing
and if and if they want to raise on our
list well they can contact us and we can
connect with them
but this is what we know so i think i
would recommend
not doing that initially because
if you have okay here are the good decks
right if you just have a list of here
are the good guys
and if you want to buy ethically or
invest ethically
these are the places to go then
the other companies who aren't on that
list are going to wait a minute
maybe we should you know see about
getting on this list maybe we should
change our ways you know it would be an
incentive whereas if you're actually
saying
bad things about them you know that
these are the bottom feeders or whatever
that can get into a lot of unnecessary
you know lawsuits or whatever true
at the same time as a consumer if i go
there to use it
and one company has a score one
company's not there i'm not instantly
going to assume they're bad i'll just be
like oh i don't know so i can't compare
those two as opposed to if you have a
profile for both
one has a score of 90 and one has a
score of four oh
all right they've looked at this company
and i don't really want to do business
based on what i know
but i do agree that that opens up
potential legal issues with that company
not
liking their score and possibly suing
you to
alleviate it right would you be
including what people are investing
on where they're investing in what
they're doing because like i know all of
the companies who probably do good
well than that but they've got
investment portfolios which
which involve like arms deals and stuff
like that so would you be kidding
with that company's investing money into
idea that's that's the ideal model
that might not be so ideally i would
like to see like a
and this is my infatuation with hollow
chain because i think
it's kind of cool but it could it could
show all those connections everywhere
and it could come up and and show it to
you to turn it around and see
everything and if if if it's money is
going out somewhere and it's and you
don't know about it then it becomes
great the more gray a company has
um the less reliable and trust me you
can put in that
but i think it's it's important kerry to
eventually have that
may not have that in the beginning okay
i just want to have one question mark
about um you're talking about an app
right
so you you're talking about developing a
an app for a smartphone
is that correct you're muted
yes yes okay so
my understanding and i'm not a technical
guy but my understanding is that
first you develop something for an
iphone and then
once that's developed then you develop
something for
that is also usable on android
now that i wouldn't recommend that um
i'm a developer um and and really
especially if you're starting out you're
and you have a low if you have an app
that does not require any special
features for the phone
and you're you're especially if you're
starting out in a in a low
cost endeavor or startup or something
with without a lot of funding then you
develop an
app and a technology that can run on all
platforms
yeah yeah it so it'd be a website and
it'd be an app for iphone and android
there's several technologies you can do
to do that
and so when mark is saying app
you know the first version would
probably be a web
app so just on the web and then you
could you can
create a shortcut on your phone and use
it on your phone like a built-in app and
then if we have money
we would then deploy that to uh
android and iphone stores and the
microsoft store
yeah that's great thank you for that
because the reason i
ask is because um when i started my
online farmers market i was
first looking at well maybe i should
just create an app and when i got into
it was like oh man the you know the
development
curve and the amount of money necessary
to actually build
a smartphone app you know before you
even know if you've got market fit
is kind of ridiculous so you know after
spent wasting two years talking to
programmers i found out you know what
i could build the damn ecommerce
platform myself
in woocommerce for a thousand bucks and
i just weighed it in and did it myself
right yep and i told people
you know if they wanted it on their
smartphone well just you know drag the
url
to the to your to your home screen and
then you can come to us anytime just by
hitting the button
because it because the website is mobile
friendly
so that saved me about two hundred
thousand dollars in about five years of
development
i'm just to bring it up just that's
absolutely true
and all those developers who told you
that gave you that advice were
less than ethical
as an example of all this i brought up
the b-corp site on my phone
and it's working just fine right so i
think that's sort of an example of
starting with a website
and i'm sure that the site works fine on
iphones as well
um and then if i think too bad at least
point it's just if you know like you
want to
access certain features of the phone
like you know the camera or gps or
something like that
you might start to get into oh okay now
we need an app but if all i'm doing is
trying to define a company a website
should work fine
i just wanted to uh highlight we had
asked if anyone else knew of anything
like this this is not for businesses
necessarily but i'm guessing it was
daniel
said charitynavigator.org helps you find
charities i was on there a bit trying to
find the wii
charity because canada's had a bit of
controversy with them to see how they
scored but then it just brought up every
list of any
charity that has we in it so i don't
quite know but just wanted to offer that
to our listeners and to to mark for for
that
charity charitynavigator.org
in that vein there's also effective
altruists
um uh they have it's not the name of
their
charity picker but they they have
uh they they try and pick charities
based on the most
evidence-based impact on the world
uh if you search effective altruists it
would come up a camera what's called
and uh quite a few charities
um and some of them were quite touchy
but he still got the funding and he
still got looked as if
oh yeah we're all singing and dancing
and all good and that so i'm a bit
dubious
about charities
how do you know what do you mean oh just
in terms of
operating um and have the operators and
how to treat
people uh because there's one i used to
work for
for homeless and not and basically most
of these homeless charities
um they'll roll it out because of being
homeless myself so i kind of know
they kind of roll it out for pr purposes
they're all singing and dancing to the
outside people
but obviously those who sort of like
involved and who they said they're going
to help
and they didn't really they didn't
really help that much you know what i
mean but the public perception of them
is oh they're great they're doing this
they're doing that
so you won't see any of that listed on
any of the b
corps or any of the charity navigators
you know i mean because nobody wants to
rock the boat and
you know call them out or whatever you
know what i mean so that's all i'm
saying
about would crowdsourcing get around
that
do you think well well i think i think
it would because i'm i think yeah
right if you're going down the chassis
route then you've got all the forms and
everything else you'd have to fill in
and you've got to jump to somebody
else's tune right
and even when you go down as i said once
you go down investors you've got to
basically do it do as they say
right because they'll be wanting money
back as well so
if if they want you to do something
unethical because you've already took
the money off them
you're gonna have to do that to deliver
now so your ass is theirs
you know i mean so that's why i was
thinking and maybe crowdsourcing would
be better
because then you'd know it actually owns
you know be a collective or a
co-op or something rather than sort of
like having investors
i think that would well i'd be more
happy with
sort of like collective co-op rather
than
investors or going down the charity
route
as well because i wouldn't i obviously
oh you know i'd never i'd never touch
another charity with a barge pole in
terms of support and that
you know like as you see these people on
the streets who collect money with the
tins
they call them chuggers in the uk right
and you see them on the street
collecting right
they're run by marketing companies who
basically say to the charity right
how much marketing how much you do you
want to earn this year
so they give them a total so anything up
over and above what what those
sugars on the street get goes back to
the marketing company
the charity doesn't even see that bit
but nobody knows about that because
nobody says fuck all ey
so that's why i'm kind of dubious about
the charity sector
and all that shit and to that extent
even the money that makes it to the
charity
there's some charities that are
notoriously bad for spending like 90
of the money they raise on
administrative costs yeah and
mostly sort of like ceo salaries as well
yeah and bonuses yeah all that stuff and
it's like
they spend where i pulled up a list i
don't want to say any company names just
in case but like
there's one example that's apparently
like a knockoff of the make a wish
foundation where they spent 600 000
granting wishes in 2010 and spent 10
times on fundraisers
yeah so i i don't want to be part of any
charity thing
because as i said i've seen the bullshit
from the inside well
this type of a project is great for that
because a lot of this is available in
numbers
like this list of you know the best and
worries charities
that that's based on stuff they have to
report and the fact that that you know
they're forced to report so that you can
go look and say
show me the worst charities if you were
to list charities on a site or like on
an
app like this you could probably fairly
easily figure out what the percentage
they spend on administrative costs and
you know towards their actual goal
and then have that be a part of the
score for charities so you can say oh
that charity is great they spend you
know 75
on their actual you know goal cool that
that's fine all that one gives
95 to administrative costs and salaries
not so cool
so i just want to bring the conversation
back to mark's
um questions so we have 20 minutes left
what would you like to focus on mark
what would you like us to
think about and crowdsource for for you
well um
actually this uh i'm still in the in the
in the wide net mode so
i'm not i'm not too um
what is it i'm not too bothered by
the direction it's it's it's gone we've
gone down a rabbit hole as far as
charities have gone a little bit but
it brings me back i'm just wondering uh
would radical transparency
would that radical transparency module
cover all
a lot of this if we could get that
filled plus the crowdsourcing
just the amount of horsepower that's
gone in
to getting that information that we
talked about has been a good
demonstration of how
the app could have addressed a lot of
this
you know there like we're six people or
eight
however many that have are
really concerned about how we spend and
how we spend our money and and just
bothered by the amount of
malevolence that's out there you know
people that are that
we we and we don't want to help them in
their tasks so
uh again this is just showing me that so
i'm willing to let this
kind of take whatever direction yeah all
right
if i may i'll just just some input on
this
i think initially if you you know
we haven't really clearly defined pain
yet anyway okay
but we have a sense that it's
it's something that's good for people
and planet
essentially okay as a minimum criteria
and the only publicly public places
where that sort of
intention is documented or tracked or
whatever
is with the b lab certified c corps
and those entities that are
legally registered as social enterprises
in the form of public benefit
corporations
or social purpose corporations and i
think you know rather than
making the project too initially
ambitious
and time consuming if you want to get
something out there
my recommendation would be to focus on
those two things and get those get all
the data for that and then get some
feedback and do an
iterative process at that point an agile
process
um i guess i hear what you're saying and
that that was something that i
thought initially too that i was excited
when i contacted b
lab i was like you know um
let's get something going um i want to
just trumpet it from the hills
and uh again they they just seem very
very reluctant
um you don't need their permission i
know i know
but their reluctance makes me think it
just gives me a little bit of pause
i i ben bentley had brought something up
because it just happened it kind of
bubbled up from the top and we circled
back to it
that it feels like
the trust thing is a big thing and
what we know and who we trust seems to
be
the small local businesses and we all
seem to kind of want to give them
prominence and points and all the help
we can
so i yeah i i would i would eventually i
would like to see
be corp and the benefit corporations on
there and i think that's a good idea
as well as the other sources where
people can
go and check these things out but i
really i would really like to see the
small
local businesses that people think are
doing well
brought up to the floor i don't know
what that just put that out there
yeah that that makes sense my my only
other thing would be
one of the major benefits that i foresee
in an app like this
is to encourage the larger corporations
to start to get ethical yes i just i
just posted an article on facebook where
the maker of gilead of rendezvir
are withholding something that works
better because they can make more money
on friend destiny
right this is a public you know
this is a company that has a public
trust we're in the middle of a pandemic
and these fuckers want to make more
money because this this
drug is going to make more money than
the one that they're withholding
right that's criminal although
technically they could be sued if they
didn't
yeah exactly they could be sued if they
didn't whereas the two were a problem
with our
legal system if they were you know be
labs
certified as a b corp that data would be
publicly transparent
oh hold on just back up a second just i
i just found that interesting
bentley did you say that they could be
sued if they only
had that that corporation's only
legal responsibility is to make profit
for their owners
and if they fail to anyone even who's
not an owner of the company who is not a
stockholder can
form a suit against them for not
supporting that
because they're publicly registered yeah
if they're a public
american corporation
there's a huge mission in what you want
to do
just by exposing that kind of crap
you know the companies that have a a
public trust
like that and scaring
other profiteers and extractionists
from being caught in the same public
reputation trap
yeah yeah i mean that i think is really
a worthwhile purpose
yeah i think on that note something that
i find interesting i'm not sure if your
plans
have any spot for this mark but to not
just talk about the companies but also
the people that make the decisions
like if we know you know who's the owner
who's the board who like
that sort of thing because there's times
where a company might make terrible
choices well a company
can't make choices people do and if
those people leave and go to a different
company and better people
join that company who should those
actions fall
in and it might be both it might say
well this company did that and even
though the people responsible left
that's still a part of their history but
also here's the people that voted for
that action or to the extent that
information is available
and now here's a company they're a part
of so in in the programming world
that that um that person is an
object that's connected to other objects
and but you can always trace
the past actions of that one object and
then maybe you could see a history of
the objects that are um that are in
influential positions in a company and
just know the potential for disaster
just looking at that
all there yeah that's a really good
point because you've got interlocking
directorates you know a lot of
companies that you know want to do
social engineering or whatever
they have these front groups that have a
really nice sounding social name but
you know they're up to no good so who
actually owns this
and what's the mother companies and you
know that sort of thing
that would be fascinating
sort of me starting with who the app is
for and getting very focused on it
whether it's for investing whether it's
for
um the person who's who is purchasing a
product because most of us don't care
about the company we decide we don't
care about the company i'm just not
purchasing based on the company because
i have to buy my cereal
for that kind of thing then because i
think all of these are very big
ideas that we all want but where do you
start because if you're starting with
um what what harrison's talking about
that or then we want to start with this
500 smp companies right like and start
mark
marking them and we're not looking at
game b whereas if we wanted we want to
bring
um business to really good companies
that are more local then you start with
that and that's kind of also
like harrison's actual project right of
like the the online farmers market that
would be focused on food and such
but like start with one and then it
broadens out
which one do you want to start with and
maybe this we're still casting a net but
which one kind of speaks to you more
i you know when when you talk about the
products
there there's nothing stopping you from
uh having a list of products
and and their parent companies as well
and so you could you could have a lot of
products on there and
the companies that are related them and
you can make your buying decision just
based on that
you know if you have a database of
you could easily have a database of a
majority of the most popular products
out there
yeah so so it sounds like your your goal
is saying the
the the user of the site the primary
user the target would be
the consumer the ethical
conscious consumer i think you could
include
uh social investors as well those two
publics
well you have to you have to have one
target
and it has to be knit small and then you
can have a second target
after that so yeah as a secondary target
you could do that but
it's it's it's considered
more efficient to choose a specific uh
well i
like some of these smaller companies if
that's one of your priorities
one of their biggest problems is getting
funding and finding social impact
investors
i mean there's a lot of there's billions
of dollars out there for social
uh social impact but how does
you know how do they link up right well
if they're producing a product this can
serve this app could serve as
a place for social impact investors to
see these little guys who are doing
great things and then
um you know funnel some funds to them if
that's one of your objectives
yeah i i think that if you have
if you start with those two objectives
you'll be
it'll double the cost of of what you're
doing
and so i think you should pick one
mark your meeting
mark you're muted
there you go yeah i'm
i hear what you're saying uh but i'm
thinking of
myself and i'm both of those what
harrison is saying i'm
i'm both of those in in i'm the curious
person
i'm three things uh at least but i'm the
curious person
i'm i'm um the consumer
but i'm also the investor
always actively looking for a way to
find a company like i
i will drive out of my way
to spend money with with uh a store
that i think is is making the world a
better place well
okay let's clarify though that's
consuming that's not
are you currently investing are you are
you giving
are you are you investing money
in a social enterprise right now that
you expect to get refunds back
for i've been trying for 20 years
to try and um untangle
the the back story so i could find
because i've tried i've tried ethical
funds and then when you when you look at
them you find
that they're not what you think they are
you know um
so i i as a consumer i think i
i consume products but i i'm also
consuming
these financial products so i think it's
still apparent
right but you still you would still be a
consumer of the financial product then
the financial product would choose the
businesses
so you're not the you're not the first
to be in charge of the financial project
choosing the businesses so you're not
the target of what harrison is
suggesting
i think start like focusing on consumers
will help investors
because one of the main things that an
investor wants to know is do consumers
want this
and if they can use information on that
site to say hey here's the people who
are doing good
and then if there's some element of like
here's other you know how many of our
members have shopped here or something
like that
that can start to give some element of
oh i as an investor might want to
invest ethically this site has also
those companies and here's the ones that
those members are finding the most
you know the most interesting and buying
the emails from
to me as an investor that would be you
know a really important
buying signal and you'd probably do it
to other stuff too but i just think that
that's the tie
the key of choosing a single target for
when you're starting a project is that
you will get
other targets hit by that like adriel's
saying it's just which one are you
focusing on so that you can
right you can be more efficient the use
of your time and
yeah it's you know sort of like the if
you focus exactly what that person needs
you're a lot more likely to be able to
achieve it as opposed to you know i'll
give three features for
for consumers and three features for
investors and three features for
businesses
it gets messy and then consumers
probably won't use it
yes just on
that um from a marketing and also sort
of a startup
perspective i agree with that like and i
will add to that
um what is the clarified what is the
benefit for each of those
users your main user consumers and um
and then as the cyber secondary audience
or user
the investors and then just like spell
that out
uh what exactly do they get
and it could be two three things it
doesn't have to be
one thing that can be distilled later on
but that also helps in the communication
and and feeling the the idea down the
line
just letting everybody know um alejandra
it comes from
a marketing background just just tell
everybody
what you're doing that for now and she
just made a big career change
yes i did i am well i come from
advertising
and digital marketing and working for
digital agencies and startups and
my kids are screaming at me right now
i'm sorry but
um i made a career change now i'm
working on
climate communication so i went to from
an eye agency to
back to non-profit which i actually
that's where i started
so i've been doing full circle i'm very
happy about that
yes so that's her wheelhouse
i just wanna i just wanted to say uh if
the intention is to provide a place
where people can find
ethical companies that it's going to
serve the purpose of both consumers and
curious investors so you know focusing
on
focusing on consumers would be good but
you know
if you're going to list products then
you know you start duplicating
things like consumer reports and gets
into
all of that so that's kind of a
different
activity i mean you could have links you
could pull it in pull the data in
on products but if you're going to
actually do product evaluation
that's a really big ask i just thought
of a third option
with what alejandra just shared
that we as people are kind of products
too
that like when i'm looking for somebody
to hire to do coding or to do marketing
if i'm paying them i mean i'd rather be
volunteer because i know you're
passionate about it
but when i'm looking to pay i want to
know i'm looking for a game b
person even a game b electrician and a
game b plumber right
like that level could be somewhere to
start i know it's not i just
wanted to throw that out there that if
you started there then it kind of leads
both into product and
company because then it's like oh wait
this is a grouping of plumbers and a
grouping of that but that's probably
going i just wanted to share well it's
it's actually
close to what adriel brought up and um
is is that um i suppose if if
decision makers and things like that are
are
objects in this in this kind of
world then um it could track
some of that but maybe not down to the
plumber level but
possibly i don't know um it it depends
on what is
cost effective to design i guess but
it's yes i meant more starting there
that like as someone who when if we're
hiring people for game b
projects or game b anything then
starting with people who
i mean how to but then it's it brings
everything else up like
how do i know you're a good person how
do i know your game be but okay i mean
in your case the people are still
businesses because if it's a software
developer
you're paying them for it that's a
that's a business
and they just have one product so it's
still not at the product level but yeah
small business when we say small
business that can go down to individual
contractors if we want to allow that
um and yeah and i i kind of like the
idea
of starting out well i i mean i think if
it's going to be open and crowdsourced
it needs to be opened and crowdsourced
and we then we have to figure out
moderation but
you know encouraging through the through
the
marketing of the site to say hey if you
know a good business a good small
business
or even local then then
here's a place to post it um
but anyway so that's that's my thought i
don't know if it's good we're also at
the hour mark
so we're at the hour mark mark okay
no this this was very very useful again
uh a lot a lot of information that i
i feel like it's um it's both
expanding a little bit but just just a
little more not much
but it's it's it's we've also narrowed
down
uh so it and we never even talked about
the private dicks
[Laughter]
it's actually an important point the
idea that
we want to um have this spread like
wildfire
by empowering people to uh
be what kerry calls the private dicks
to go out and um investigate feel like
they're making a change
by contributing to this list and this
this growing database and crowdsourcing
and
and and having something you know you
can train them
give them some basic training on on what
to look for
and then you have a maybe a a network of
people that they
they can say hey i have this question
and then it just it just gets looked at
right and so they have
something backing them up they can go
out there and actually you know be
heavyweights because not only are they
trained a little bit but they have this
kind of
this network of people 2 000 people at
least in the background
going yeah i can weigh in on that i know
a little bit about that and stuff like
that
anyways that's where you want to start
mark getting a group of people together
who want to do that
you're gonna it's going to emerge what
they like when they're doing research
what it is that they can find out about
a company
so even finding a handful of those
people and then working from that point
to create it
can be right yeah yeah
online spreadsheet yeah i think that's
that's
probably um what was going to happen
with the first
um narrowing down meeting anyways
is just a post on some of these things
and an invitation for people to
to uh weigh in and
it would be good if we could have that
thing adrian was talking about
where if you know they're a bank of
ideas and everybody can see
their idea on their and their suggestion
and where it was
in the whole scheme of things but also
finding a way to organically build
this network of of uh we're gonna have
to find a different name kerry
private dicks i just don't think will or
maybe it should stay that way i don't
know
but well what i was thinking right in in
terms of
the private decks that the target
audience would be
stay-at-home moms right
stay-at-home moms who've got who you
know we want to get the best products
for the kids
alejandro will back me up here stay at
home mum's right you've got all these
mums networks out there
who want the right thing you want people
to do the right thing and
lord behold anyone who doesn't do the
right thing okay so
and train them to be the private dicks
you know what i mean and then have an
army of these um
private dick mothers you know we're just
going out saying oh you're a shitty
company
i'm gonna say we could call it the exact
opposite of private dicks but i won't
anyway public public vaginas
sorry um and with that we're going to
stop the recording because
the person whose internet this is
probably has to get back to work and we
can continue the conversation though
but thank you everyone else for showing
up and this was an amazing conversation
we're here tomorrow for our round tables
at 9am on saturday
same youtube and facebook group